Guide to the Dean S. Wright Collection, 1957 - 1965, 1995
University Archives Duke University
Dean S. Wright collection 1957 - 1965, 1995
Wright, Dean Scanlan, 1941-2002.
0.25 Linear Feet 100 Items
University Archives, Duke University
Dean Wright played football for the Duke University Blue Devils from 1958 to 1961. During this time, the Duke football team earned two consecutive ACC Championships (1960 and 1961) and won the Cotton Bowl (1961). Dean Wright received many honors as an outstanding player, including the Team MVP Award and invitations to play in the honorary North-South Game (1961) and in the All-America Game (1962). The Dean S. Wright Collection consists of clippings, correspondence, awards, memorabilia, photographs, game programs, and a textbook, which document Dean Wright's student life and football career, Head Football Coach Bill Murray, and the Duke University football team from 1958 to 1962.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
No restrictions.
Provenance
The Dean S. Wright Collection was received by Duke University as a gift from Vivian Wright in 2003.
Biographical Note
Dean Scanlan Wright was born in Brownsville, Texas on February 14, 1941, and grew up in Coral Gables, Florida. He attended Duke University and earned a psychology degree in 1962. While at Duke, Wright played football for the Blue Devils from 1958 to 1961, as halfback. During this time, the Duke football team earned two consecutive ACC Championships (1960 and 1961) and won the Cotton Bowl (1961). Dean Wright received many honors as an outstanding player, including the Team MVP Award and invitations to play in the honorary North-South Game (1961) and in the All-America Game (1962).
After college, Wright was drafted into the National Football League to play for the Houston Oilers, but he injured his knee after one season and returned to Florida. Wright then became a pilot, flying for a number of airlines during his career. Dean Wright died on March 31, 2002 in Coral Gables, Florida. He was survived by his wife, Vivian Wright.
Collection Overview
The Dean S. Wright Collection features awards, correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, game programs, and a textbook, but the bulk of the collection is made up of clippings. These clippings consist of newspaper and magazine articles collected by Dean Wright, his family, and friends from a variety of sources. These include local papers, such as the Duke Chronicle, the Durham Morning Herald, the Raleigh News and Observer, and the Charlotte Times, as well as regional and national press, such as the New York Times, the Miami Herald, the Dallas Morning News, and the Buffalo Evening News. These clippings and other materials document Dean Wright's student life and football career, Head Football Coach Bill Murray, and the Duke University football team from 1958 to 1962.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Wright, Dean Scanlan, 1941-2002
Atlantic Coast Conference
Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae
Duke University. Dept. of Athletics
Duke University -- Football
College sports -- North Carolina
Cotton Bowl, Dallas, Tex. (Football game)
Football players -- North Carolina -- Durham
Clippings
Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Awards, 1960-1961 and undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1957- Sept. 1962
    Includes Wright's student housing assignment, welcome letters from Duke Football players and coaches, and an invitation to the North-South Game.
  - Memorabilia, 1958-1961
    Includes game tickets, Duke University fee statement and course card.
  - Photographs, ca. 1958-1962
    Includes 8 photos of Dean Wright playing football and receiving awards.
    [Photographs stored with University Archives Photograph Collection. One oversize photograph stored in MC drawer 25.]
  - Football Game Programs, 1961, 1962, 1965
    Programs include invitational "All-Star" games played or attended by Dean Wright, but not by the Duke football team. Duke Football programs for regular home, away, and tournament games, can be found in the Dept. of Athletics Records.
    - North-South College All-Star Football Game, Dec. 25, 1961
      Includes North-South game ticket and game patch.
    - All-America Game, June 29, 1962
    - North-South College All-Star Football Game, Dec. 25, 1965
  - Textbook: A Guide to Sea Power, Dept. of Naval Science, Duke University, 1960
    Textbook published as an instructional aid for the use of midshipmen in the Depts. of Naval Science at the University of North Carolina and Duke University.
  - Clippings, 1958-1962, 1995 and undated
    These clippings consist of newspaper and magazine articles collected from local, regional, and national sources, which document Dean Wright's student life and football career and the Duke University football team from 1958 to 1962.
    - 1958-1959
    - 1960
    - 1961
    - 1962, 1995 and undated
Related Material
Dept. of Athletics Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Office of Sports Information Subject Files.
University Archives, Duke University.